MICHAL DOBROWOLSKI

Product Designer

michal.dobrowolski@outlook.com | +48 507 668 664

I have 10 years of experience in UX Design. Over the years, I worked on a wide variety of projects, from simple mobile apps, through product websites and complex enterprise solutions.

I am competent to work on every stage of the design process, from user research, problem and strategy definition, through iterative interaction design and hypothesis validation.

When I am not working, I enjoy playing video games with my wife. Most recently, Bit Sabre in VR.

CORE SKILLS

Communication

Gathering requirements, working with dev team and communicating design.

Product roadmap

Working with the team on the planning and execution of the product strategy.

Reasearch & validation

Conducting various types of research; interviews, shadowing, usability tests.

Design systems

Creating and maintaining shared components: principles, branding, and practices.

Data analysis

Preparing topics for analysis and reviewing data sets to understand users.

Prototyping

Shaping the design hypotheses on various levels of fidelity, from sketches to interactive prototypes.

CURRENT POSITION

Principal User Experience Specialist

January 2018 - Present @ Syncron Poland

I am the lead designer for one of our main products - Inventory. It is an enterprise solution for supply chain inventory optimization. My projects revolve around: charts, Gaussian distribution, data visualization, tables, filtering, searching and facilitation of various workflows.

Most of the projects begin with: hypothesis followed by research with the users, design workshops, information architecture, prototype design (Axure, Sketch) and validation.

In April 2019, I was promoted from Senior User Experience Specialist.

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the European Parliament's and Council of the European Union Regulation on the Protection of Natural Persons as of 27 April 2016, with regard to the processing of personal data and on the free movement of such data, and repealing Directive 95/46/EC (Data Protection Directive).

PAST WORK EXPERIENCE

User Experience Designer

July 2016 - October 2017 @ William Hill in Gibraltar, United Kingdom

I worked on a few key features of an online betting website: horse racing, lottery, user registration; customer support solutions: faq, chat and account recovery. All of these projects were done for both mobile and desktop.

User Experience Designer

December 2013 - June 2016 @ e-point

I was the lead designer for various ING Bank projects (RWD, branch and atm locator app, stock quotes app). I was also working with Amway on their e-commerce solutions (search feature, product catalogue and private informational content distribution platform).

User Experience Designer / Interaction Designer

May 2009 - November 2013 @ Multiple companies

During the first 4 years of my career I worked in a few design agencies and software houses. Large majority of my time there I spent on the delivery of prototypes, diagrams, documentation and guidelines for the developers.

EDUCATION

Trainee

February 2020 @ Progress Project

- AgilePM® Foundation (certified training)
- Stress management and emotion control

Continuous professional improvement

Since the beginning of my career

I participate in various workshops and online courses. I read books and articles on daily basis. If I want to improve upon my weaknesses, I actively put myself in situations where I can improve. For example, I wanted to run better workshops, so I started offering free Axure training.

Engineer of Information management

October 2007 - January 2011 @ Polish-Japanese Institute of Information Technologies

The curriculum comprised of subjects related to management, economics and information technology. During my studies I gained skills of managing modern enterprises and projects, as well as solving various problems encountered in organisations.

AFTER WORK ACTIVITIES

Mentor

October 2019 - Present @ Tech Leaders (Women in Technology Programme)

I am humbled to be a mentor to a fantastic person who wants to begin their career in tech. We work together on a project and learn from one another.

Lecturer

October 2019 - Present @ Coders Lab

Teaching students about various aspects of interaction design and prototyping.

Lecturer

October 2013 - Present @ SWPS University

Teaching students about various topics related to UX: from personas, scenarios, through IA, benchmarking, design systems and tools such as Axure and Sketch.

Organizer and speaker

October 2013 - Present @ UX Book Club Warsaw

Responsible for choosing a topic, organization of the event and meeting coordination.

Organizer and speaker

October 2012 - Present @ Design Tools Workshops

Teaching participants how to use Sketch, Axure and Figma.

Guest lecturer

February 2019 - March 2019 @ School of Form

Tought students about basics and key concepts of User Experiece Design.

Guest lecturer

October 2015 - May 2016 @ Polish-Japanese Institute of Information Technologies

Tought students about basics and key concepts of User Experiece Design.

Volunteer

June 2011 - November 2013 @ Animal shelter

I was responsible for cleaning cages, taking the dogs out for a walk, reading books to them, and occasionally creating dog adoption ads.